<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Manual_ERPNext.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts">
<title>Accounts</title>
<para>At the end of sales and purchase cycle comes billing and payments. You may have an accountant in your team, or you may
	be doing accounting yourself, or you may have outsourced your accounting. In all the cases financial accounting forms the
	core of any business management system like an ERP.</para>
<para>In ERPNext, your accounting operations consists of 3 main transactions:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Sales Invoice: The bills that you raise to your Customers for the products or services you provide.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Purchase Invoice: Bills that your Suppliers give you for their products or services.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Journal Vouchers: For accounting entries, like payments, credit and other types.</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Introduction">
<title>Introduction to Accounting</title>
<para>People new to accounting are often confused with the terms Debit and Credit. Contrary to their meaning, these terms have
			nothing to do with who owes what.</para>
<sect2>
<title>Debit and Credit</title>
<para>Debit and Credit are conventions. All accounting follows these, so that it is easy to understand the state of finances in
	a universal manner. These conventions are:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>All Accounts are of type Debit or Credit.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Assets and Expenses (and their sub-groups) are always Debit.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Liabilities and Income (and their sub-groups) are always Credit.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>In all accounting entries, you “debit” an Account or “credit” one.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>When you “debit” a Debit Account (an asset or expense), its value increases (“add” operation). When you “credit” a Debit Account,
	its value decreases (“subtract” operation). The same rule applies for Credit Accounts. “Crediting” a Credit Account, increases its
	value, “debiting” it decreases its value.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>All accounting transactions (like a sales or a payment) must affect at least two different Accounts and sum of debits must be
	equal to sum of credits for the transaction. This is called the “double-entry bookkeeping system”.</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Still confused? These conventions will become clear as you make transactions.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title>Accrual System</title>
<para>Another important concept to understand in Accounting is accrual. This is important when your payment happens separately from
	delivery.</para>
<para>For example, you buy X from a Supplier and your Supplier sends you a bill and expects you to pay in, for example, seven days.
	Even if you have not yet paid your Supplier, your expense must be booked immediately. This expense is booked against a group of
	Accounts called “Accounts Payable” that is the sum of all your outstanding dues to your Suppliers. This is called accrual. When you
	pay your Supplier, you will cancel his dues and update your bank account.</para>
<para>ERPNext works on an accrual system. The transactions that accrue income and expense are Sales Invoice and Purchase
	Invoice.</para>
<para>In retail, typically, delivery and payment happens at the same time. To cover this scenario, we have in ERPNext a POS Invoice
	(POS = Point of Sales). More on that later.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Sales">
<title>Sales</title>
<para>A Sales Invoice is a bill that you send to your customers, against which the customer processes the payment. Sales Invoice is an
	accounting transaction. On submission of Sales Invoice, the system updates the receivable and books income against a Customer Account.
</para>
<para>You can create a Sales Invoice directly from</para>
<programlisting>Accounting > Documents > Sales Invoice > New Sales Invoice</programlisting>
<para>or Click on Make Invoice at the right hand corner of the Delivery Note.</para>
<sect2>
<title>Accounting Impact</title>
<para>All Sales must be booked against an “Income Account”. This refers to an Account in the “Income” section of your Chart of Accounts.
	It is a good practice to classify your income by type (like product income, service income etc). The Income Account must be set for
	each row of the Items table.</para>
<note><para>To set default Income Accounts for Items, you can set it in the Item or Item Group.</para></note>
<para>The other account that is affected is the Account of the Customer. That is automatically set from “Debit To” in the heading
	section.</para>
<para>You must also mention the Cost Centers in which your Income must be booked. Remember that your Cost Centers tell you the
	profitability of the different lines of business or product. You can also set a default Cost Center in the Item master.</para>
<sect3>
<title>Accounting entries (GL Entry) for a typical double entry “Sale”:</title>
<para>When booking a sale (accrual):</para>
<para>Debit: Customer (grand total) Credit: Income (net total, minus taxes for each Item) Credit: Taxes (liabilities to be paid to the
	government)</para>
<note><para>To see entries in your Sales Invoice after you “Submit”, click on “View Ledger”.</para></note>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>Dates</title>
<para>Posting Date: The date on which the Sales Invoice will affect your books of accounts i.e. your General Ledger. This will affect
	all your balances in that accounting period.</para>
<para>Due Date: The date on which the payment is due (if you have sold on credit). This can be automatically set from the Customer
	master.</para>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>Recurring Invoices</title>
<para>If you have a contract with a Customer where you bill the Customer on a monthly, quarterly, half-yearly or annual basis, you
	can check the “Recurring Invoice” box. Here you can fill in the details of how frequently you want to bill this Invoice and the
	period for which the contract is valid.</para>
<para>ERPNext will automatically create new Invoices and mail it to the email ids you set.</para>
</sect3>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title>"Pro Forma" Invoice</title>
<para>If you want to give an Invoice to a Customer to make a payment before you deliver, i.e. you operate on a payment first basis,
	you should create a Quotation and title it as a “Pro-forma Invoice” (or something similar) using the Print Heading feature.</para>
<para>“Pro Forma” means for formality. Why do this? Because if you book a Sales Invoice it will show up in your “Accounts Receivable”
	and “Income”. This is not ideal as your Customer may or may not decide to pay up. But since your Customer wants an “Invoice”, you
	could give the Customer a Quotation (in ERPNext) titled as “Pro Forma Invoice”. This way everyone is happy.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Purchase">
<title>Purchase Invoice</title>
<para>Purchase Invoice is the exact opposite of your Sales Invoice. It is the bill that your Supplier sends you for products or
	services delivered. Here you accrue expenses to your Supplier. Making a Purchase Invoice is very similar to making a
	Purchase Order.</para>
<para>To make a new Purchase Invoice, go to:</para>
<programlisting>Accounts > Documents > Purchase Invoice > New Purchase Invoice</programlisting>
<para>or click on “Make Purchase Invoice” in Purchase Order or Purchase Receipt.</para>
<note><para>The concept of “Posting Date” is again same as Sales Invoice. “Bill No” and “Bill Date” helps to track the bill number
	as set by your Supplier for reference.</para></note>
<sect2>
<title>Accounting Impact</title>
<para>Like in Sales Invoice, you have to enter an Expense or an Asset account for each row in your Items table. This helps to indicate
	if the Item is an Asset or an Expense. You must also enter a Cost Center. These can also be set in the Item master.</para>
<para>The Purchase Invoice will affect your accounts as follows:</para>
<para>Accounting entries (GL Entry) for a typical double entry “purchase”:</para>
<para>Debits:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Expense or Asset (net totals, excluding taxes)</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Taxes (assets if VAT-type or expense again).</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Credits:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Supplier</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>To see entries in your Purchase Invoice after you “Submit”, click on “View Ledger”.</para>
<sect3>
<title>Is purchase an “Expense” or an “Asset”?</title>
<para>If the Item is consumed immediately on purchase, or if it is a service, then the purchase becomes an “Expense”. For example,
	a telephone bill or travel bill is an “Expense” - it is already consumed.</para>
<para>For inventory Items, that have a value, these purchases are not yet “Expense”, because they still have a value while they
	remain in your stock. They are “Assets”. If they are raw-materials (used in a process), they will become “Expense” the moment
	they are consumed in the process. If they are to be sold to a Customer, they become “Expense” when you ship them to the
	Customer.</para>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>Deducting Taxes at Source</title>
<para>In many countries, the law may require you to deduct taxes, while paying your suppliers. These taxes could be based on a
	standard rate. Under these type of schemes, typically if a Supplier crosses a certain threshold of payment, and if the type
	of product is taxable, you may have to deduct some tax (which you pay back to your government, on your Supplier’s behalf).</para>
<para>To do this, you will have to make a new Tax Account under “Tax Liabilities” or similar and credit this Account by the
	percent you	are bound to deduct for every transaction.</para>
<important><para>Taxes are an essential part of accounting, if you are miscalculating taxes your business may be at risk of fines
	and	tax charges. If you are unsure about the calculation or application of any tax consult your accountant or tax
	specialist.</para></important>
</sect3>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Payments">
<title>Making Payments</title>
<para>Payments made against Sales Invoices or Purchase Invoices can be made by clicking on “Make Payment Entry” button on “Submitted”
	invoices.</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Update the “Bank Account” (you can also set the default account in the Company master).</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Update posting date.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Enter the cheque number, cheque date.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Save and Submit.</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
<para>Payments can also be made independent of invoices by creating a new Journal Voucher and selecting the type of payment.</para>
<para>Incoming Payment: For payments from Customers:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Debit: Bank or Cash Account</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Credit: Customer</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<note>
<para>Remember to add “Against Sales Invoice” or “Is Advance” as applicable.</para>
</note>
<para>Outgoing Payment: For payments to Suppliers:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Debit: Supplier</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Credit: Bank or Cash Account</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<sect2>
<title>Reconciling Cheque Payments</title>
<para>If you are receiving payments or making payments via cheques, the bank statements will not accurately match the dates of your
	entry, this is because the bank usually takes time to “clear” these payments. Also you may have mailed a cheque to your Supplier
	and it may be a few days before it is received and deposited by the Supplier. In ERPNext you can synchronize your bank statements
	and your Journal Vouchers using the “Bank Reconciliation” tool.</para>
<para>To use this, go to:</para>
<programlisting>Accounts > Tools > Bank Reconciliation</programlisting>
<para>Select your “Bank” Account and enter the dates of your statement. Here you will get all the “Bank Voucher” type entries. In each
	of the entry on the right most column, update the “Clearance Date” and click on “Update”.</para>
<para>By doing this you will be able to sync your bank statements and entries into the system.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title>Managing Outstanding Payments</title>
<para>In most cases, apart from retail sales, billing and payments are separate activities. There are several combinations in which
	these payments are done. These cases apply to both sales and purchases.</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>They can be upfront (100% in advance).</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Post shipment. Either on delivery or within a few days of delivery.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Part in advance and part on or post delivery.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Payments can be made together for a bunch of invoices.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Advances can be given together for a bunch of invoices (and can be split across invoices).</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>ERPNext allows you to manage all these scenarios. All accounting entries (GL Entry) can be made against a Sales Invoice,
	Purchase Invoice or Journal Vouchers (in special cases, an invoice can be made via a Sales Invoice too).</para>
<para>The total outstanding amount against an invoice is the sum of all the accounting entries that are made “against” (or are linked
	to) that invoice. This way you can combine or split payments in Journal Vouchers to manage the scenarios.</para>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title>Matching Payments to Invoices</title>
<para>In complex scenarios, especially in the capital goods industry, sometimes there is no direct link between payments and invoices.
You send invoices to your Customers and your Customer sends you block payments or payments based on some schedule that is not linked
to your invoices.</para>
<para>In such cases, you can use the Payment to Invoice Matching Tool.</para>
<programlisting>Accounts > Tools > Payment Reconciliation</programlisting>
<para>In this tool, you can select an account (your Customer’s account) and click on “Pull Payment Entries” and it will select all
	un-linked Journal Vouchers and Sales Invoices from that Customer.</para>
<para>To cancel off some payments and invoices, select the Invoices and Journal Vouchers and click on “Reconcile”.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Advance">
<title>Advance Payment Entry</title>
<para>Payment done by the customer before accepting delivery of the product is an Advance Payment. For Orders of high value, the
	business houses expect to receive advance.</para>
<para>For Example: Consider a customer- Jane D'souza placing an order for a double bed costing Rs 100000/- She is asked to give
	some advance before the furniture house begins work on her order. She gives them Rs 1000/- in cash.</para>
<para>Go to Accounts and open a new Journal Voucher to make the advance entry.</para>
<programlisting>Accounts > Documents > Journal Voucher > New Journal Voucher</programlisting>
<para>Mention the voucher type as cash voucher. This differs for different customers. If somebody pays by cheque the voucher type
	will be Bank Voucher. Then select the customer account and make the respective debit and credit entries.</para>
<para>Since the customer has given 10000/- as cash advance,it will be recorded as a credit entry against the customer. To balance
	it with the debit entry[Double accounting Entry]enter 10000/- as debit against the company's cash account. In the row "Is Advance"
	click 'Yes'.</para>
<sect2>
<title>Double Entry Accounting</title>
<para>Double entry bookkeeping is a system of accounting in which every transaction has a corresponding positive and negative entry :
	debits and credits. Every transaction involves a debit entry in one account and a credit entry in another account. This means that
	every transaction must be recorded in two accounts; one account will be debited because it receives value and the other account will
	be credited because it has given value.</para>
<para>Save and submit the JV. If this document is not saved it will not be pulled in other accounting documents.</para>
<para>When you make a new Sales Invoice for the same customer, mention the advance in the Sales Invoice Form.</para>
<para>To link the Sales Invoice to the Journal Voucher which mentions the advance payment entry, click on ‘Get Advances Received’.
	Allocate the amount of advance in the advances table. The accounting will be adjusted accordingly.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Journal">
<title>Journal Vouchers</title>
<para>All types of accounting entries other than Sales Invoice and Purchase Invoice are made using the Journal Voucher. A Journal
	Voucher (also called Journal Entry) is a standard accounting transaction that affects multiple Accounts and the sum of debits is
	equal to the sum of credits.</para>
<para>To create a Journal Voucher go to:</para>
<programlisting>Accounts > Documents > Journal Voucher > New Journal Voucher</programlisting>
<para>In a Journal Voucher, you must select.</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Type of Voucher from the drop down.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Add rows for the individual accounting entries. In each row, you must specify:</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<orderedlist>
<listitem>
<para>The Account that will be affected.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>The amount to Debit or Credit.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>The Cost Center (if it is an Income or Expense).</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Against Voucher: Link it to a voucher or invoice if it affects the “outstanding” amount of that invoice.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Is Advance: Select “Yes” if you want to make it selectable in an Invoice.  Other information in case it is a Bank Payment or a
	bill.</para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
<para>Difference: The “Difference” field is the difference between the Debit and Credit amounts. This should be zero if the Journal
	Voucher is to be “Submitted”. If this number is not zero, you can click on “Make Difference Entry” to add a new row with the amount
	required to make the total as zero.</para>
<sect2>
<title>Common Entries</title>
<para>A look at some of the common accounting entries that can be done via Journal Voucher.</para>
<sect3>
<title>Expenses (non accruing)</title>
<para>Many times it may not be necessary to accrue an expense, but it can be directly booked against an expense Account on payment.
	For example a travel allowance or a telephone bill. You can directly debit Telephone Expense (instead of your telephone company)
	and credit your Bank on payment.</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Debit: Expense Account (like Telephone expense).</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Credit: Bank or Cash Account.</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>Bad Debts or Write Offs</title>
<para>If you are writing off an Invoice as a bad debt, you can create a Journal Voucher similar to a Payment, except instead of
	debiting your Bank, you can debit an Expense Account called Bad Debts.</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<para>Debit: Bad Debts Written Off.</para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Credit: Asset (the Account under which you had booked the asset to be depreciated).</para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<note><para>There may be regulations in your country that define by how much amount you can depreciate a class of Assets.</para></note>
</sect3>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Credit">
<title>Credit Limit</title>
<para>A credit limit is the maximum amount of credit that a financial institution or other lender will extend to a debtor for a
	particular line of credit. From an organisation's perspective, it is the maximum amount of credit which a customer gets on goods
	purchased.</para>
<para>To set credit limit go to Customer- Master</para>
<programlisting>Selling > Document > Customer</programlisting>
<para>Go to the 'More Info section' and enter the amount in the field Credit Limit.</para>
<para>In case a need arises to allow more credit to the customer as a good-will, the Credit Controller has access to submit
	order even if credit limit is crossed.</para>
<para>To allow any other role to submit transactions by customers whose credit limit has expired, go to accounting settings and make
	changes.</para>
<para>In the field Credit Controller, select the role who would be authorized to accept orders or raise credit limits of
	customers.</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Openning">
<title>Openning Entry</title>
<para>If you are a new company you can start using ERPNext accounting module by going to chart of accounts.</para>
<para>However, if you are migrating from a legacy accounting system like Tally or a Fox Pro based software, you need to "Open" your
	 Accounting.</para>
<sect2>
<title>Opening Accounts</title>
<para>Now that you have completed most of the setup, its time to start moving in!</para>
<para>There are two important sets of data you need to enter before you start your operations.</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Opening Account balances.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Opening Stock balances.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>To setup your accounts and stock correctly you will need accurate data to work with. Make sure you have the data setup for
	this.</para>
<sect3>
<title>Opening Accounts</title>
<para>We usually recommend that you start using accounting in a new financial year, but you could start midway too. To setup your
	accounts, you will need the following for the “day” you start using accounting in ERPNext:</para>
<para>Opening capital accounts - like your shareholder’s (or owner’) capital, loans, bank balances on that day. List of outstanding
	sales and purchase invoices (Payables and Receivables).</para>
<para>Based on Voucher Type</para>
<para>You can select accounts based on the voucher type. In such a scenario, your balance sheet should be balanced.</para>
<para>Also, note that if there are more than 300 ledgers, the system will crash. Thus to avoid such a situation, you can open accounts
	by using temporary accounts.</para>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>Temporary Accounts</title>
<para>A nice way to simplify opening is to use a temporary account just for opening. These accounts will become zero once all your
	old invoices and opening balances of bank, debt stock etc are entered. In the standard chart of accounts, a Temperory Opening
	account is created under assets</para>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>The Opening Entry</title>
<para>In ERPNext Opening Accounts are setup by submitting a special Journal Entries (Journal Voucher).</para>
<note><para>Make sure to set “Is Opening” as “Yes” in the More Info section.</para></note>
<programlisting>Setup > Opening Accounts and Stock > Opening Accounting Entries.</programlisting>
<para>Complete Journal Entries on the Debit and Credit side.</para>
<para>To update opening balance is to make Journal Voucher for an individual/group of accounts. For example, if you want to update
	balance in three bank accounts, then make Journal Vouchers in this manner.</para>
<para>Temporary Asset and Liability account is used for balancing purpose. When you update opening balance in Liability Account, you
	can use Temporary Asset Account for balancing. This way, you can update opening balance in Asset and Liability accounts.</para>
<para>You can make two Opening Journal Vouchers:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>For all assets (excluding Accounts Receivables): This entry will contain all your assets except the amounts you are
	expecting from your Customers against outstanding Sales Invoices. You will have to update your receivables by making an individual
	entry for each Invoice (this is because, the system will help you track the invoices which are yet to be paid). You can credit the
	sum of all these debits against the Temperory Opening account.</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>For all liabilities: Similarly you need to pass a Journal Voucher for your Opening Liabilities (except for the bills you have
	to pay) against Temperory Opening account.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>In this method you can update opening balance of specific balancesheet accounts and not for all.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<note><para>Opening entry is only for balance sheet accounts and not for expense or Income accounts.</para></note>
</sect3>
<sect3>
<title>Outstanding Invoices</title>
<para>After your Opening Journal Vouchers are made, you will need to enter each Sales Invoice and Purchase Invoice that is yet to
	be paid. Since you have already booked the income or expense on these invoices in the previous period, select the temp opening
	account Temporary Opening in the “Income” and “Expense” accounts.</para>
<important><para>Make sure to set each invoice as “Is Opening”!</para></important>
<para>If you don’t care what items are in that invoice, just make a dummy item entry in the Invoice. Item code in the Invoice is not
	necessary, so it should not be such a problem.</para>
<note><para>Once all your invoices are entered, your Temperory Opening account will have a balance of zero!</para></note>
</sect3>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Closing">
<title>Closing a Financial Period</title>
<para>At the end of every year or (quarterly or maybe even monthly), after completing auditing, you can close your books of accounts.
	This means that you make all your special entries like:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Depreciation</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Change in value of Assets</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Defer taxes and liabilities</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Update bad debts</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>etc. and book your Profit or Loss.</para>
<para>By doing this, your balance in your Income and Expense Accounts become zero. You start a new Fiscal Year (or period) with
	a balanced Balance Sheet and fresh Profit and Loss account. In ERPNext after making all the special entries via Journal Voucher
	for the current fiscal year, you should set all your Income and Expense accounts to zero via:</para>
<programlisting>Accounts > Tools > Period Closing Voucher</programlisting>
<para>Posting Date will be when this entry should be executed. If your Fiscal Year ends on 31st December, then that date should be
	selected as Posting Date in the Period Closing Voucher.</para>
<para>Transaction Date will be Period Closing Voucher's creation date.</para>
<para>Closing Fiscal Year will be an year for which you are closing your financial statement.</para>
<para>This voucher will transfer Profit or Loss (availed from PL statment) to Closing Account Head. You should select a libility
	account like Reserves and Surplus, or Capital Fund account as Closing Account.</para>
<para>The Period Closing Voucher will make accounting entries (GL Entry) making all your Income and Expense Accounts zero and
	transferring Profit/Loss balance to the Closing Account.</para>
<important><para>If accounting entries are made in a closing fiscal year, even after Period Closing Voucher was created for that
	Fiscal Year, you should create another Period Closing Voucher. Later voucher will only transfer the pending PL balance into Closing
	Account Head.</para></important>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Accounts-Reports">
<title>Accounting Reports</title>
<para>Some of the major accounting reports are:</para>
<para>General Ledger: General Ledger is based on the table GL Entry and can be filtered by Account and between a period. This will
	help you to get a full update for all entries done in that period for that Account.</para>
<para>Trial Balance: Trial Balance is the list of Account balances for all your Accounts (“Ledger” and “Group”) on a particular date.
	For each Account it will give you the:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Opening</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Debits</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Credits</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Closing</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>The sum of all closing balances in a Trial Balance must be zero.</para>
<para>Accounts Payable and Accounts Receivable (AP / AR): These reports help you to track the outstanding invoices sent to Customer
	and Suppliers. In this report, you will get your outstanding amounts period wise. i.e. between 0-30 days, 30-60 days and so on.
	You can also get your payables and receivables from direct reports on Sales Invoice and Purchase Invoice.</para>
<para>Sales and Purchase Register: In this report, each tax Account is transposed in columns. For each Invoice and invoice Item,
	you will get the amount of individual tax that has been paid, based on the Taxes and Charges table.</para>
</sect1>
</chapter>
