<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Manual_ERPNext.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying">
<title>Buying</title>
<para>If your business involves physical goods, buying is one of your core business activity. Your suppliers are as important
	as your customers and they must be provided with as much accurate information as possible. Buying in right amounts, in right
	quantities, can affect your cash flow and profitability. ERPNext contains a set of transactions that will make your buying
	process as efficient and seamless as possible.</para>
<sect1>
<title>Buying Settings</title>
<para>Buying Settings is where you can define properties which will be applied in the Buying module's transactions.</para>
<para>Let us look at the various options that can be configured:</para>
<orderedlist>
<listitem><para>Supplier Naming By: When a Supplier is saved, system generates a unique identity or name for that Supplier
	which can be used to refer the Supplier in various Buying transactions.If not configured otherwise, ERPNext uses the
	Supplier's Name as the unique name. If you want to identify Suppliers using names like SUPP-00001, SUPP-00002, or such
	other patterned series, select the value of Supplier Naming By as "Naming Series".You can define or select the Naming
	Series pattern from:<programlisting>Setup > Settings > Naming Series</programlisting></para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Default Supplier Type: Configure what should be the value of Supplier Type when a new Supplier is
	created.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Default Buying Price List: Configure what should be the value of Buying Price List when a new Buying
	transaction is created.</para></listitem>
<listitem>
<para>Maintain Same Rate Throughout Purchase Cycle: If this is checked, ERPNext will stop you if you change the Item's
	price in a Purchase Invoice or Purchase Receipt created based on a Purchase Order, i.e. it will maintain the same price
	throughout the purchase cycle. If there is a requirement where you need the Item's price to change, you should uncheck
	this option.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Purchase Order Required: If this option is configured "Yes", ERPNext will prevent you from creating a
	Purchase Invoice or a Purchase Receipt without first creating a Purchase Order.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Purchase Receipt Required: If this option is configured "Yes", ERPNext will prevent you from creating a
	Purchase Invoice without first creating a Purchase Receipt.</para></listitem>
</orderedlist>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying-Type">
<title>Supplier Type</title>
<para>A supplier may be distinguished from a contractor or subcontractor, who commonly adds specialized input to deliverables.
	A supplier is also known as a vendor. There are different types of suppliers based on their goods and products. ERPNext allows
	you to create your own categories of suppliers. These categories are known as Supplier Type. For Example, if your suppliers are
	mainly pharmaceutical companies and FMCG distributors, You can create a new Type for them and name them accordingly. Based on
	what the suppliers supply, they are classified into different categories called Supplier Type. There can be different types of
	suppliers. You can create your own category of Supplier Type.</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Setup > Supplier Type > New Supplier Type</programlisting>
<para>You can classify your suppliers from a range of choice available in ERPNext. Choose from a set of given options like Distributor,
	Electrical,Hardware, Local, Pharmaceutical, Raw material, Services etc. Classifying your supplier into different types facilitates
	accounting and payments.</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying-Master">
<title>Supplier Master</title>
<para>Suppliers are companies or individuals who provide you with products or services. They are treated in exactly the same manner as
	Customers in ERPNext. You can create a new Supplier via:</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Documents > Supplier > New Supplier</programlisting>
<sect2>
<title>Contacts and Addresses</title>
<para>Contacts and Addresses in ERPNext are stored separately so that you can attach multiple Contacts or Addresses to Customers and
	Suppliers. To add a Contact or Address go to Buying and click on “New Contact” or “New Address”.</para>
<note><para>When you select a Supplier in any transaction, one Contact and Address gets pre-selected. This is the “Default Contact or
	Address”. So make sure you set your defaults correctly!</para></note>
</sect2>
<sect2>
<title>Integration with Accounts</title>
<para>In ERPNext, there is a separate Account record for each Supplier, of Each company. When you create a new Supplier, ERPNext
	will automatically create an Account Ledger for the Supplier under “Accounts Payable” in the Company set in the Supplier
	record.</para>
	<important><para>If you want to change the Account Group under which the Supplier Account is created, you can set it in the
		Company master.</para></important>
<para>If you want to create an Account in another Company, just change the Company value and “Save” the Supplier again.</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Contact > New Contact</programlisting>
<para>You can also import from the Data Import Tool</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying-Request">
<title>Material Request</title>
<para>A Material Request is a simple document identifying a requirement of a set of Items (products or services) for a particular
	reason. To generate a Material Request manually go to:</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Documents > Material Request > New Material Request</programlisting>
<para>A Material Request can be generated:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>By a User.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Automatically from a Sales Order.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Automatically when the Projected Quantity of an Item in stores reaches a particular level.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Automatically from your Bill of Materials if you use Production Plan to plan your manufacturing
	activities.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>In the Material Request form:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Fill in the Items you want and their quantities.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If your Items are inventory items, you must also mention the Warehouse where you expect these Items to be delivered.
	This helps to keep track of the Projected Quantity for this Item.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>You can optionally add the Terms, using the Terms and Conditions master and also the reason.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<note><para>Material Request is not mandatory. It is ideal if you have centralized buying so that you can collect this information
	from various departments.</para></note>
<sect2>
<title>Authorization</title>
<para>If you want your Material Request to be authorized by a senior person like a Purchase Manager then you can give “Submit” rights
	only to that person. Everyone can create requests, but only the authorized person can “Submit”.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying-Quotation">
<title>Supplier Quotation</title>
<para>A Supplier Quotation is a formal statement of promise by potential supplier to supply the goods or services required by a
	buyer, at specified prices, and within a specified period. A quotation may also contain terms of sale and payment, and warranties.
	Acceptance of quotation by the buyer constitutes an agreement binding on both parties. You can make a supplier quotation from a
	Material Request</para>
<para>You can also make a Supplier Quotation directly from:</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Documents > Supplier Quotation > New Supplier Quotation</programlisting>
<para>If you have multiple Suppliers who supply you with the same Item, you usually send out a message (Request for Quote) to various
	Suppliers. In many cases, especially if you have centralized buying, you may want to record all the quotes so that:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>You can easily compare prices in the future.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Audit whether all Suppliers were given the opportunity to quote.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>Supplier Quotations are not necessary for most small businesses. Always evaluate the cost of collecting information to the
	value it really provides! You could only do this for high value items.</para>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying-Order">
<title>Purchase Order</title>
<para>A Purchase Order is analogous to a Sales Order. It is usually a binding contract with your Supplier that you promise to buy
	a set of Items under the given conditions. A Purchase Order can be automatically created from a Material Request or Supplier
	Quotation.</para>
<para>In ERPNext, you can also make a Purchase Order directly by going to:</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Documents > Purchase Order > New Purchase Order</programlisting>
<para>Entering a Purchase Order is very similar to a Purchase Request, additionally you will have to set:</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Supplier</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>A “Required By” date on each Item: If you are expecting part delivery, your Supplier will know how
	much quantity to deliver at which date. This will help you from preventing over-supply. It will also help you to track
	how well your Supplier is doing on timeliness.</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<sect2>
<title>Taxes</title>
<para>If your Supplier is going to charge you additional taxes or charge like a shipping or insurance charge, you can add it here.
	It will help you to accurately track your costs. Also, if some of these charges add to the value of the product you will have to
	mention them in the Taxes table. You can also use templates for your taxes. For more information on setting up your taxes see the
	Purchase Taxes and Charges Master.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Buying-Taxes">
<title>Purchase Taxes</title>
<para>For Tax Accounts that you want to use in the tax templates, you must mention them as type “Tax” in your Chart of Accounts.
	Similar to your Sales Taxes and Charges Master is the Purchase Taxes and Charges Master. This is the tax template that you can
	use in your Purchase Orders and Purchase Invoices.</para>
<programlisting>Buying > Setup > Purchase Taxes and Charges Master > New Purchase Taxes and Charges Master</programlisting>
<para>You can specify if the tax / charge is only for valuation (not a part of total) or only for total (does not add value
	to the item) or for both. If you select a particular tax as your Default tax, the system will apply this tax to all the
	purchase transactions by default.</para>
<sect2>
<title>Calculation Type</title>
<para>This can be on Net Total (that is the sum of basic amount). On Previous Row Total / Amount (for cumulative taxes or charges).
	If you select this option, the tax will be applied as a percentage of the previous row (in the tax table) amount or total. Actual
	(as mentioned).</para>
<para>Account Head: The Account ledger under which this tax will be booked.</para>
<para>Cost Center: If the tax / charge is an income (like shipping) or expense it needs to be booked against a Cost Center.</para>
<para>Description: Description of the tax (that will be printed in invoices / quotes).</para>
<para>Rate: Tax rate.</para>
<para>Amount: Tax amount.</para>
<para>Total: Cumulative total to this point.</para>
<para>Enter Row: If based on "Previous Row Total" you can select the row number which will be taken as a base for this calculation
	(default is the previous row).</para>
<para>Consider Tax or Charge for: In this section you can specify if the tax / charge is only for valuation (not a part of total) or
	only for total (does not add value to the item) or for both.</para>
<para>Add or Deduct: Whether you want to add or deduct the tax.</para>
</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1>
<title>Buying Process</title>
<para>The first step to complete a buying cicle is to create a Supplier
and some Items in the inventory, to create a supplier in the Buying 
module select "Supplier"</para>
<para>In the suppliers list select new.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras001.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Fill the basic supplier information.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras002.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Click in save.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras003.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Now we have a supplier we need to create some items to buy,
in the Buying module select Items</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras004.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>In the item list select new</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras005.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Fill the basic item data and click save.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras006.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>To create a new supplier invoice we must go the accountin module and
select Supplier Bill</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras008.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Select New</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras009.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Fill the Supplier and items info.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras010.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Click in save.</para>
<para>This will save the bill in as a draft, to record the transaction to
the system click in Present.</para>
<para>We can verify than we have a record in the inventory versus a payable
account.</para>
<para>To procces the suplier pay in the accountin module select Payable
bills and the select the bill you want to pay and select Pay entry, click in New.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras011.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras012.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Fill the paymen information and click in Save.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras013.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
<para>Click in present to record the transaction.</para>
<para>Puede validar que el pago fue aplicado.</para>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="./images/compras014.png" />
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</sect1>
</chapter>
