<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Manual_ERPNext.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration">
	<title>Collaboration Tools</title>
	<para>
	We live in an era when people are very comfortable communicating, discussing, asking, assigning work and getting feedback electronically. The Internet acts as a great medium to collaborate on work too. Taking this concept into ERP system, we have designed a bunch of tools whereby you can Assign transactions, manage your To Dos, share and maintain a Calendar, maintain a company wise Knowledge Base, Tag and Comment on transactions and send your Orders, Invoices etc via Email. You can also send instant messages to other users using the Messaging tool.
	</para>
	<para>
	These tools are integrated into all aspects of the product so that you can effectively manage your data and collaborate with your co-workers.
	</para>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration-ToDo">
		<title>To Do</title>
		<para>
		To Do is a simple tool where all the activities assigned to you and assigned by you are listed. You can also add your own to-do items in the list.
		</para>
		<para>
		When task is completed, you should simply remove assignment from the assigned document. With this, task will be removed from your Todo list as well. For Todo which are not assigned via document, you can set their status as Closed from the Todo record itself.
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration-Messages">
		<title>Messages</title>
		<para>
		You can send and receive messages from the system by using the Messages tool. If you send a message to a user, and the user is logged in, it will appear as a popup message and the unread messages counter in the top toolbar will be updated.
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration-Notes">
		<title>Notes</title>
		<para>
		You can store your long notes under this section. It can contain your partner lists, frequently used passwords, terms and conditions, or any other document which needs to be shared. Following are the steps to create new Note. To create a new note, go to:
		</para>
		<programlisting>Home > Note > New</programlisting>
		<note>
		<para>Notes can also be used as a knowledge base internally. You can also attach file in the Notes, and make it accessible to specific set of users only.</para>
		</note>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration-Calendar">
		<title>Calendar</title>
		<para>
		The Calendar is a tool where you can create and share Events and also see auto-generated events from the system. You can switch calender view based on Month, Week and Day.
		</para>
		<sect2>
			<title>Creating Events in Calender</title>
			<para>
			There are many options to add events to the calendar
			</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration-Assignment">
		<title>Assignmet</title>
		<para>
		Text
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Collaboration-Tags">
		<title>Tags</title>
		<para>
		Text
		</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
