<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Manual_ERPNext.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Stock">
	<title>Stock</title>
	<para>
	For most small business that deal in physical goods, a large part of their net worth is invested in the stock in hand.
	</para>
	<para>
	There are three main types of entries:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Purchase Receipt: Items received from Suppliers against Purchase Orders.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Stock Entry: Items transferred from one Warehouse to another.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Delivery Note: Items shipped to Customers.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
	Tracking stock is not just about adding and subtracting quantities. Some complications arise when:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Back-dated (past) entries are made / edited: This affects future stock levels and may lead to negative stock.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Stock has to be valued based on First-in-First-out: ERPNext needs to maintain a sequence of all transactions to know the exact value of your Items.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Stock reports are required at any point in time in the past: You have to lookup what was the quantity / value your stock of Item X on date Y.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
	To manage this, ERPNext collects all inventory transactions in a table called the Stock Ledger Entry. All Purchase Receipts, Stock Entries and Delivery Notes update this table.
	</para>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Stock-Item">
		<title>Item Master</title>
		<para>
		An Item is your companys' product or a service. The term Item is applicable to your core products as well as your raw materials. It can be a product or service that you buy/sell from your customers/ suppliers. ERPNext allows you to manage all sorts of items like raw-materials, sub-assemblies, finished goods, item variants and service items.
		</para>
		<para>
		ERPNext is optimized for itemized management of your sales and purchase. If you are in services, you can create an Item for each services that your offer. Completing the Item Master is very essential for successful implementation of ERPNext.
		</para>
		<sect2 id="sect2-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Stock-Item-Codification">
		<title>Item Codification</title>
		<para>
		If you already have a full-fledged business with a number of physical items, you would have probably coded your items. If you have not, you have a choice. We recommend that you should codify if you have lot of products with long or complicated names. In case you have few products with short names, it is preferable to keep the Item Code same as Item Name.
		</para>
		<para>
		Item codification has been a sensitive topic and wars have been fought on this (not joking). In our experience, when you have items that cross a certain size, life without codification is a nightmare.
		</para>
                </sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
	<title>Stock Entry</title>
	<para>
	A Stock Entry is a simple document that lets you record Item movement from a Warehouse, to a Warehouse and between Warehouses. To make a Stock Entry you have to go to:
	</para>
	<programlisting>Stock > Stock Entry > New</programlisting>
	<para>
	Stock > Stock Entry > New
	</para>
	<para>
	<itemizedlist>
	<listitem><para>Material Issue - If the material is being issued. (Outgoing Material)</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Material Receipt - If the material is being received. (Incoming Material)</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Material Transfer - If the material is being moved from one warehouse to another.</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Material Transfer for Manufacturing - If the material being transfered is for Manufacturing Process.</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Manufacture - If the Material is being received from a Manufacturing/Production Operation.</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Repack - If the Original item/items is being repacked into new item/items.</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Subcontract - If the Material is being issued for a sub-contract activity.</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Sales Return - If the Material that was sold was returned by the customer.</para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>Purchase Return - If you have returned a material supplied by a supplier.</para></listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<para>
	In the Stock Entry you have to update the Items table with all your transactions. For each row, you must enter a “Source Warehouse” or a “Target Warehouse” or both (if you are recording a movement).
	</para>
	<note>
	<para>To update Stock from a spreadsheet, see Stock Reconciliation.</para>
	</note>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="sect1-ERPNext-Manual_ERPNext-Stock-Purchase">
	<title>Purchase Receipt</title>
	<para>
	Purchase Receipts are made when you accept material from your Supplier usually against a Purchase Order. You can also accept Purchase Receipts directly ( Set Purchase Order Required as “No” in Global Defaults).
	</para>
	<para>
	You can make a Purchase Receipt directly from:
	</para>
	<programlisting>Stock > Purchase Receipt > New Purchase Receipt
	</programlisting>
	<para>
	or from a “Submitted” Purchase Order, by clicking on “Make Purchase Receipt”.
	</para>
		<sect2>
			<title>UOM Conversions</title>
			<para>
			If your Purchase Order for an Item is in a different Unit of Measure (UOM) than what you stock (Stock UOM), then you will need to update the “UOM Conversion Factor”.
			</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
		<title>Stock UOM Replace Utility</title>
		<para>
		This tool will help you to change the UOM (Unit of measurement) of an existing Item.
		</para>
		<para>
		You need to select an Item, system fetches the Existing UOM of that item. You can then select the new UOM for that item 
+and specify the conversion factor.
		</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
